ladies and gentlemen
a very warm welcome to ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q2 and
H1 fy23 earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr bhargav dasgupta MD and CEO
of the company
Mr gopal balachandran CFO and cro
Mr Sanjeev mandri executive director
wal executive director
please note that any statements comments
are made in today's calls that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management
and do not constitute an indication of
any future performance as future
involved risk and uncertainties which
could cause results to defer materially
from the current views being expressed
as a reminder
all participant lines will be in the
listen early mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your Touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
I now have the conference over to Mr
bhargav Das Gupta mdn CEO ICICI hello my
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over the user
uh thank you and good evening to each
one of you thank you for joining the
earnings conference call of ips number
General Insurance Company Limited for
the second quarter and half years of fi
23.
I will give you a brief overview of the
industry Trends and developments that we
have witnessed in the last few months
post this our CFO Mr gopal balance will
share the financial performance of the
companies in a quarter and happier ended
September 30 2022
domestically the economic activity has
been Gathering fees and the recovery is
evidenced by the The High Frequency
indicators in the industrial and the
services sector
the Improvement in consumption spending
is expected to be sustained by strong
festive demand and possible Improvement
in rural consumption in the second half
of the year
the systemic credit is quite robust and
broad-based
at the same time head will strong
geopolitical tensions tightening Global
Financial conditions strong dollar and
elevated Global inflation is slowing
Global demand resulting into lower
Imports which may have an adverse impact
on economic Indian economic growth in
the near term
so the data has been published by CM the
new vehicle sales with the strong growth
for private cars fragment and it's
easing supply chain constraints and
festive demand
the commercial vehicle segment grew
robustly supported by underlying demand
while the two wheeler segment continue
to remain slow compared to the
pre-pandemic levels
health insurance continually drives the
overall industry growth
the commercial lines witnessed growth in
line with the current market environment
we remain optimistic that the industries
will continue to grow given the lower
Insurance penetration positive consumer
sentiment and enhanced risk awareness
as a result the GI industry delivered a
gdpi growth of 15.3 percent for the
first half of this year over the first
half of last year
excluding crop insurance this growth is
at 18 for the same period
however we continue to see pricing
regression in certain segments like
Motors while there is some improvement
in group health segment for motor
business combined ratio for the industry
was 124.5 percent and quarter one of
f523 as compared to 107.1 for quarter
one of fy22 as for public disclosures
overall the combined ratio of the
industry improved from 11
11.4 in quarter one of 2023 as compared
to 124.0 in quarter 1 of 2022.
in the recent past the authority has
announced several reforms to increase in
Insurance penetration in the country
during the quarter The Authority has
issued and proposed the following
changes one the exposure draft on
expensive management and payment of
commission regulations proposing an
aggregate limit at a company level
to master guidelines on AML including
kyc requirements along with establishing
internal policies procedures controls
and compliance Arrangements effective
November 1st 2022
number three increase in the number of
tires from three to nine in case of
corporate agents for each category of
insurance
number four other four forms of capital
wherein insurers can raise Capital by
way of reference shares or supportive
debt without having to Avail prior
approval of the Authority number five
amendments to the regulatory sandbox the
sandbox regulations eliminating time
limit to facilitate innovation in
products or Solutions
and to increase the experimental period
up to 36 months these are all under
consideration and we believe that these
and many other changes have been made or
are being proposed which will have a
significant positive effect on product
Innovation ease of doing business and
insurance penetration
moving to business impact for us during
the quarter the company grew by 22.6
percent as compared to the industry
growth of 15.3 percent
coming to the growth of key segments
during the quarter
in motor growth remain tapered at 4.5
percent we continue to combat challenges
like heightened comparative intensity in
the motor owned damage side we remain
focused on growing our market share in
certain key profitable sub segments
within motor overall new vehicle sales
have been strong and demand sentiment
also continues to be positive
we are optimistic that with the
improving pricing environment we will be
able to consolidate leadership position
given our strength of distribution in
this segment
our investment in retail Health
distribution resulted in growth of 15.8
percent as against eight point zero
percent quarter one or five twenty three
within the quarter we have outgrown the
industry and Standalone players for the
month of September with the growth of
21.1 this was driven by growth of
business forced by retail health agency
vertical of 30.7 in the quarter two of
fi 23.
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop One-Stop solution for all
insurance and wellness needs I'll take
care as surface 2.7 million user
downloads till date the incremental
download for the quarter was 1 million
our bank issues and key relationship
grew at 36.1 percent of this quarter
within this its a Bank distribution grew
at 33.9 and non-ic Bank distribution
grew by 37.6 percent
post pandemics the recovery in credit
along with the increase in volunteer and
distribution Partners acquired through
the demerger has been the pgo growth
driver
our business source through our digital
one team grew by 24.5 percent
overall our digital Focus has enabled us
to increase our digital revenues from to
uh 2.26 billion rupees which happens for
about 4.4 percent of our overall gdpa
for the quarter
as for the As far as the commercial
lines are concerned we experience
Rover's growth driven by 26.9 growth in
the SMA segment
we remain on track and are focused on
growth levers such as launching new
products strengthening our distribution
engine digital enhancements realizing
Synergy rationalizing cost wise carrying
up our preferred lines of business
I will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
Recently concluded quarter thanks uh
good evening to each one of you uh I
will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for Quarter Two and H1 FY 2023
the results presentations are already
put up on the stock exchanges and if we
are in the process of putting up putting
it on the website of the company you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers
[Music]
against rupees 86.13 billion in H1 fy22
a growth of 22.6 percent
this growth was higher than the industry
growth of 15.3 percent
GDP was at rupees 51.85 billion in Q2
f523 as against rupees 44.24 billion in
q2f by 22. a growth of 17.2 percent this
growth was higher than the district
growth of 10 percent
a gdpi growth of spring was primarily
driven by growth in preferred segments
the overall GDP of our Property and
Casualty segment grew by 16 at rupees
32.13 billion in H1 f523 as against
rupees 27.69 billion in H1 f522
on the retail side of the business the
GDP of the motor segment was at rupees
37.09 billion in H1 f523 as the gained
rupees 32.46 billion in H1 f522
registering a growth of 14.3 percent
our agents which included which include
the point of sale count for the first
time
across one lakh to one lakh 636 as on
September 30 2022 from 94 559 as on June
30 2022.
as against
33.68 billion rupees as at March 31 2022
there's certainly the combined ratio of
104.6 in H1 API 23 as against one one
four point three percent in H1 fy22
excluding the impact of cyclone and
flood losses of
0.28 billion the combined ratio was
104.2 percent in H1 fy23 as against 113
in h1f by 22 excluding the impact of
cyclone and flood losses of rupees point
eight two billion
excluding the impact of Blood and
Cyclone losses of rupees 0.28 billion
the combined ratio was 104.3 percent in
q2f by 23 as against 103.7 in Q2 f522
excludes that again excludes the impact
of cyclone and blood losses of rupees
0.5 billion
our investment asset Rose to rupees
400.96 billion as in September 1322 from
398.34 billion as at June 3022 the
investment leverage net of borrowings
was 4.08 times
22.
investment income was at 13.94 billion
in H1 f523 as against rupees 16.05
billion in H1 f522 on a quarterly basis
investment income increased to rupees
7.39 billion in q2523 as against rupees
7.16 billion in Q2 f522
investment income of quarter to f523
includes impairment on Equity investment
assets of RS 0.89 billion as per the
company policy
our capital gain net of impairment on
Equity investment assets stood at rupees
1.43 billion in H1 fy23 as compared to
rupees 4.71 billion in H1 fy22
capital gains net of impairment on
Equity investment assist in quarter to
FY 23 was lower at rupees 1.11 billion
as compared to rupees 1.44 billion in
quarter to fy22
our profit before tax grew by 26.1
percent that rupees 10.75 billion in H1
fy23 as again rupees 8.52 billion in H1
f522
whereas profit before tax
grew by 2.7 percent it will be 6.1
billion in quarter to 2523 as against
rupees 5.9 billion nine four billion in
q2f522
consequently profit after that grew by
46.6 at rupees 9.40 billion in H1 f523
as against 26.41 billion H1 f522 whereas
profit after tax blew by 32.2 percent at
rupees 5.91 billion in Q2 f523 from
rupees 4.47 billion in quarter to f522
profit after tax for future 523 includes
reversal of tax provision of rupees 1.28
billion excluding this growth in profit
after tax was 26.5 and 3.4 percent for
H1 and Q2 fy23 respectively
return on average Equity was 19.9 in H1
f523 has against 15.2 percent in H1 F by
22. the return on equity for first
quarter two fy23 was 24.5 percent as
against 21 in quarter to f522 excluding
the reversal of tax provision the return
on average equity for H1 and Q2 fy23 was
at 17.3 and 19.3 respectively
it's always the ratio was at 2.47 times
as a September 30 22 as against two
point six point times rather June 30 22
continues to be higher than the
regulatory minimum of 1.5 times
the board of directors of the company
has declared interim dividend of rupees
4.5 percent for H1 FY 2023
the company has exercised the call
option to redeem the debentures of
rupees 2.20 billion in full along with
the final interest due post receipt of
necessary regulatory or such three
approvals on June July 7 2022. the
recording for the same was August 7 2022
thus outstanding debentures thanks that
rupees 0.35 billion as at September 30
2022. as I conclude I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
profitable growth sustainable valuation
and safeguarding the interest of policy
holders at all times
I would like to thank you for attending
this earnings call and will be happy to
take any questions if you may ask thank
you
thank you very much sir
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question the
press star and one on your Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star and do
participants are requested to use
answers while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question Q assembles
the first question is from the line of
swarna Mukherjee from bnk Securities
please go ahead
yeah hi uh thank you for the opportunity
sir uh yeah I have three questions first
of all uh the flow through from uh gross
written premium to Net10 premium so I
can see that there have been uh
sequentially higher retention level
during the quarter and also
also we replace some uh
if you could highlight what explains
this that would be my first question
second is of the motor book so the gdpi
mix shows that there is a higher share
of private Vehicles again
um if you could throw some light of what
is going on there and what is the reason
behind the DP loss ratio the outcome
particular sure and thirdly uh on the
crop craft portfolio so we have reached
at 800 crore kind of a number in first
half I think uh you had mentioned
earlier that you want to spend 100 of
what RTX heavy I used to do in crop so
does that mean that there would not be
any other premium inflows in crop uh
going ahead in the second half so these
are the three questions
thank you let me take the uh third
question and I'll ask gopal to answer
the first and we'll jointly give you
handle the second
um on the crop business it's a seasonal
you know mix Curry is usually bigger and
the point that we had made earlier was
that crop business will remain about
five five plus minus five percent of our
of our portfolio I don't think there's
going to be any change in that so second
half of the year the amount of problems
will be significantly lower than this
number that you see in the first half
again the principle that we are
following is the business that came from
baji which had a Serial commitment that
we are maintaining
and apart from that uh the new business
that we've written is largely on the or
entirely on the 1810 Model A Certain
States as you know have shifted to 1810
model where the cost of reinsurance for
us is significantly lower because of the
natural limit of loss at 110. so that's
what we have written but the mix of the
business will be uh you know will be
much more in the first half compared to
the second half overall guidance that we
had given in terms of composition of the
mix of portfolio that doesn't change
ratio higher uh so if you look at I
think uh quarter one typically is a
period of commercial policy anyways
where the extent of reinsurance support
are relatively higher and that's the
reason why you find quarter one
detention ratios to be relatively lower
than Q2 Q2 is more a book where you also
get to see a higher proportion of retail
business coming through and hence to
that extent sequentially is why you find
the retention ratios for Quarter Two to
be higher than quarters one otherwise in
that sense there is is largely to do
with the kind of assessment that we have
for Q2 relative to q1 so your second
point on uh in terms of an expired risk
Reserve releases being slightly elevated
I think that's primarily again a
function of so again no change in the
way we kind of earn revenues it's over
the period of the contract as one of
your questions was in the context of
crop booking given the fact that Karim
season typically has a shorter time
cycle when it comes to earning of
revenues and as to that extent you will
obviously find an elevated levels of
earnings coming through in Quarter Two
having said that obviously you also kind
of given the fact in line with what you
explained in so far as the loss
experiences are concerned unless until
we don't have the complete estimate of
the claims experience till that point of
time we obviously continue to provide
for losses at 100 of the earnings that
has happened so that's primarily the
reason why you get to see uh slightly
elevated earnings as compared to let's
say maybe the relative period that
you're looking at on the motor uh let me
maybe take it uh you know the mix of the
business is in line with what we had
indicated at the beginning of the year
and in the last conference call uh you
know I don't know where you've got this
point about private car increasing
actually it's coming down if you look at
up here first half private car was about
56.5 percent of our mix as we speak for
this year first half uh 56.5 seconds
this year is about 49.6 the increase is
largely in CV uh two minutes similar
almost 30 26.5 percent has gone to 27.1
and CV has increased from 17.1 percent
to 23.4 percent in line with what we
have been saying for the last couple of
quarters the TV mix will be uh you know
in the mid-20s uh range so given the
large dynamics that we are seeing in the
private car particularly particularly
private car motor OD is We Believe
significantly underpriced at this point
in time we've been a bit more cautious
on the private card segment and any case
as part of our strategy of increasing
our very selected TV business but that
strategy is playing out and if you see
the growth of CVS we have a very good
goal for the first half the Civic
business has gone on about 56 for us
this first half
so just to follow up on that
uh very good
yeah so uh actually uh in terms of the
meat I was talking about quarters
was
47.7 and in the first half it was 49.6
so from that point of view I was asking
whether you know you are seeing more
connection on the private vehicle sites
yeah I understood you about a little q1
yes but if you again compare with U2 to
Q2 last case and you have to look at
your YY numbers because visuality there
are festive periods where private car
does more so if you look at last year Q2
we had about 57 of weeks coming from
private car this year is 51 percent in
spite of the fact that we uh festive
season has been a bit Freeport so
actually the top relative drop is even
higher
okay okay got it
yeah yes Google please go ahead I I
think interrupted you your last point
it's your last question on with respect
to motor third party loss ratios again
fundamentally as we keep saying you
should look at loss ratios more in the
context of let's say uh year-to-date
numbers are actually full year numbers
particularly for more than that party
given that it's a long tail line of
businesses in in a particular quarter
there are various elements that goes
goes into it uh we would continue to
retreat that you have to look at the
portfolio experience more on a year to
date or as I said more on a financial
aid basis
okay so I've got it thank you thank you
sir uh that's all from my side
thank you thank you the next question is
from the lineup price chain from motilal
oswal please go ahead
yeah hi uh hi everyone uh just a few
questions from my side posted on the
health claims Health claim ratios they
have increased significantly on a
sequential basis uh so could you break
it down as to what was the reason uh
secondly uh could you throw some light
on the implementation of vehicles act
and how how is it panning out across the
country and do we see some benefits of
it coming down coming in 10 years in in
the next couple of quarters or it's a
more driven one from an extra
perspective how do we see that happening
and lastly uh could you cite the reason
for the dip in solvency you know uh on a
sequential basis that would be good
so maybe let me take this last part
first the decline in the solvency is
purely a function of what kind of growth
rates that you see and the mix of
business that you write
um so as I said I think Quarter Two
generally tends to be a portfolio mix
which is relatively more also in favor
of retail and as per the current Factor
based solvency regulations that are in
place the relative Capital requirement
for a retail business is far higher than
let's say the commercial line of
businesses so hence that's purely a
function of what kind of distance
volumes that you write but otherwise if
you see I think we are quite comfortable
with the level of solvency that we are
operating at which is about
2.47 times the second element what you
also look at in terms of impact on
solvency I think this is something that
you will get to see more or less in
every quarter two is post I mean we
declare dividend in so far as final
dividend declarations happen towards the
end of the year which gets confirmed at
the AGM and the payment happens in
Quarter Two And so prediction there is
also an outflow on account of dividend
payout which tends to have an impact in
so far as the solvency numbers are
concerned so otherwise it's a minor
sequential decline but these are the two
key factors
with respect to solvency outcomes to
your first point on the loss ratio
numbers I think when you look at health
for example
the breakup for the loss ratios for the
corporate books I am giving you quarter
two numbers quarter to fy23 numbers the
corporate or let's say the employer
employer loss ratios are at about 99.1
percent and the retail Indemnity numbers
and that's broadly the kind of uh range
that we have spoken about on the
confidence side and on retail has
Indemnity I think the last ratios for
Quarter Two is at about 64.4 percent
foreign
so there are some seasonality impact of
uh you know Monsoon and uh you know
medical acute cases you know the the
Dengue malaria and also there's usually
a spike that we always see in this
period uh so and the second point of a
sequential is that the previous quarter
there could have been some releases that
we got in that quarter uh but overall
the number is not going to be as high as
as the number that gopal talked about
for the whole year our senses that group
and this is a group of the entire
employees
not the B2B to see the bank of business
is separate but the group employer
employee loss ratio will remain in the
ballpark number that we had indicated
which is you know in the mid 90s for the
year as a whole what we are also seeing
is that uh even as we speak on a on a
base if you remember last time we used
to talk about the fact that we had to
ask for we had gone back to our client
you know corporate clients and taken
price increases uh premium per Life had
increased post covet uh and we you know
this year also on top of that we are
seeing some price increases so we are
quite comfortable with the group health
portfolio as we see it in just one
quarter number may not be fully
reflected with the book that we are
writing
your last point on motor third party
again you know there are some early
signs but it's too early for us to call
uh you know we would want to watch this
for a couple of quarters before we take
a final view on whether the motor
vehicles act implicate impact is uh
Across the Nation we are seeing some
early signs here and there but that's
not uh it's too early for us to take a
call but it's uh it's happened at a
national scale
thank you thank you so much
thanks fresh
thank you the next question is from the
line of Shreya Shivani from clsa please
go ahead
thank you uh sir I have two questions uh
first is on the uh overall growth uh I
wanted your opinion on
how should we sorry how should we build
in growth for the
full year given that for first half you
guys have grown at 23 and particularly
your health book I mean on month on one
basis you guys are writing 400 crores uh
that way so I want to understand how
sustainable this 23 is or particularly
the group sorry the health uh book of
400 crores per month is first is on that
second I wanted to understand maybe a
little bit better Insight on why is
there so much uh cyclicality or movement
in your uh investment yields between one
q and 2q like the quarterly move is
quite high if I see it over previous
years the quarters of previous years it
was in this um this wide so I wanted to
understand that as well
is running on the first one uh clearly
the growth momentum uh is higher than
what we anticipated or integral at the
beginning of the year in the first half
if you see uh we've been uh
significantly more careful about the
private car business in spite of that
we've been able to deliver the group
numbers that you are seeing
so my sense is that the health numbers
are sustainable uh you know the point
that we've been making with the
investment that we've made on the agency
distribution we are beginning to see
that uh play through if you see others
as we mentioned in our opening remarks
the agency retail health agency numbers
are picking up
Group Health we are seeing some
improvement in pricing uh some of the
large players who've been in the past
very aggressive
they are toning down their aggression on
pricing and getting a bit more
disciplined so even on a group as an
employment employee portfolio we are
seeing uh conversions at prices that we
we are comfortable with so I don't see
any constraint at the last thing on the
on the health side ICC bank has
restarted Distributing the indemnity
policy on the on the uh you know on the
on the home home site so that's why the
bank numbers are high and and the banker
overall numbers are also high for given
the tie ups that we've got through the
acquisition they are performing really
well and the credit uh you know
dismissals are higher so our attachment
businesses are also picked up so on the
health side we remain reasonably
optimistic and confident about
maintaining uh you know all performance
and growth water actually you know as I
said you know Market has been over
aggressive and I don't believe it's
sustainable we are again seeing some
players uh we celebrate on the CV side
uh further as in reduced discounts and
you know improve increased prices uh we
want to see we are seeing quite a few
players taking similar decisions the
Private Car Side equally there are a few
players who are still aggressive so if
pricing aggression gets muted on the
motor side it may give us an opportunity
to grow even faster than what we've
grown in the in this quarter that you
know again we Will Be watchful but I
don't see the numbers going below the
current growth numbers at USB so overall
we remain reasonably confident about the
growth uh you know trajectory that you
said uh I think the only you know
concern that we you know remain uh in
about the market is the pricing on the
motor on the website that is something
that you would want to watch uh a bit
closely
recorded understood
I think story is purely a function of
what kind of uh interested environment
that you see in the market I think at
this point of time we are seeing an
increasing interest rate regime and
therefore to that extent you will
obviously find the yields to kind of
fluctuate between periods so otherwise
it's purely a function of what kind of
mix of investment that we are making and
largely to do with the interest rate
environment that's operating so that
actually you will always find uh
criticality in terms of outcome so
that's one and secondly when you look at
the overall yield on the aggregate
assuming on the entire investment income
when you look at obviously it's a
function of both interest accruals as
well as capital gains and you will never
find uh evening of capital gains across
periods for example if you look at let's
say the half year numbers the capital
gains for let's say first half is just
about 100 1.43 billion this uh this half
year this number when you look at each
one of the previous series at about 471
crores so when you look at the yield on
the overall portfolio including the on a
realized basis then you will obviously
find fluctuating uh outcomes but at this
point of time when we look at it from an
overall portfolio standpoint a higher
increase higher interest rate regime
actually occurs well in so far as our
interest accruals are concerned because
typically when you look at our overall
investment income breakdown on an
average roughly about 70 to 75 percent
of our investment income is through
accruals and typically on an average
balance 25 to 30 percent is capital gain
on an annual basis within quarters
obviously there can be cyclicality with
respect to what he actually is
okay okay I'll get back in the queue
thank you
the next question is from The Lion of
nidesh from investec please go ahead
thanks for the opportunity sir uh the
two three questions firstly uh what is
the number of number of the sales that
we have done from the ielt take care you
shared that number last quarter what is
the number that we have achieved in this
quarter
downloads that we have done which are
so how are we driving that downloads are
we uh you know are we increasing any
cost to to to to make a customer
download this app and then the second
question third is uh your commentary on
the on the competitive intensity that
few players have uh become are
recalibrating that is on motor TP or
model OD uh segment uh uh that you are
seeing uh reduction in computer
intensity and if and what are your sense
that in by what time period we may start
seeing uh motor on damage component
density coming down uh given that it has
been quite intense for last couple of
years and lastly is there any comment on
the and the on the management succession
planning given that there is a
possibility of cap on CEO 10 years of 50
years these are the key questions
okay let me get the last one out uh you
know the yesterday exposure draft is
there for 15 years it's an exposure duct
if it becomes a final regulation then
obviously something will have to be done
uh but we will wait for that exposures
up to uh come true
um the second question on aggression we
are as we've mentioned I think the real
problem is in the OD segment I mean you
know we you know opening remarks we
talked about the overall combined ratio
for motor the compound ratio for motor
only is even worse than that so TP is
actually proven to be better at this
point in time
um so the aggression is in certain
segments uh and aggression gets played
out in terms of since you can't do
anything on the TP price people you know
kind of uh do higher discounting in the
OD or incur higher cost in uh in getting
that business so the problem is more in
the OD side
um the other question that you had on
I'll take care uh just to give you uh
the uh so one is the you know how we are
driving it uh what we're doing is you
know initially if you remember I'll take
your app was largely uh set up to uh you
know engage our corporate customers what
I mean by corporate customers is the
employees or corporate customers so when
we sell our group health insurance
policy it's a policy sold to a corporate
but the health insurance is for the
employees and really there was hardly
any engagement with them so that was the
original uh you know uh thought process
where we launched it about a bit more
than two years back
as we speak today more than 50 of the
employees of our corporates have
downloaded the app and use that app uh
and that but this percentage has been
increasing quarter and quarter so that's
one uh you know area where how we
prevent this the second is you know
gradually we now you know putting a lot
of effort on the uh on the bank
insurance and the agencies and the
retail side and there you know it is not
as easy to you know bring about change
because there's a behavior shift and you
know you're working with Distributors
and agents Etc but even there you are
seeing very good traction uh largely
because people are seeing value in that
engagement so so overall there is uh you
know there may be some cost per some
material but overall we are driving it
through uh basically convention we think
about it we have roughly our last name
we had about 30 million policies that we
sold right so uh you know and let's say
2.7 million download still gives us a
lot of uh Runway of growth uh you know a
lot of those numbers may be small ticket
or two other policies but still we see
that as an opportunity so
your last question on on sales sales is
something that we started only last year
so it's beginning to pick up and when we
talk about sales it's uh you know it
includes the renewals that people do on
their own on the app that number in q1
was about 9.8 crores that number has
grown roughly three times in this
quarter it's become a 27.4 crores for
this quarter and for the month of
September it was about 10 crores so we
are seeing very very good Traction in
terms of adoption engagement even in
terms of the you know the walking Track
monthly average users daily average
users uh honor your wire basis those
numbers have grown about 4X so we are
seeing very good traction with with that
app as originally as we had talked about
this being a potential game changer for
our engagement model with customers
last question on investment uh if I look
at the accrual investment deal it has
increased almost uh 80 90 basis point uh
sequentially uh so I had around 7.3 so
going forward this will be the base e
and it will continue to increase right
is that that's the right understanding
cycle play out as I kind of mentioned an
increasing interest rate regime
obviously offers well for us in so far
as in first approvals are concerned but
equally you should be mindful of the
facts that correspondingly to that
exchange from a master Market
perspective on the 16 come book you will
obviously have a market negative
and therefore the ability of us to
possibly realize any amount of capital
gain you may not see that happening so
when I kind of wave that broad split of
let's say 70 75 interest accruals and 25
30 the view of capital K that could
possibly see some kind of a change but
if this momentum of let's say interested
cycle sustains then from an overall as
slows continue to accrue from business
realization which should definitely help
in overall uh increase in the yield of
the boat yeah so maybe your point is
actually right I mean the carry deal
should keep on increasing given the yeah
it's a very positive from a longer term
perspective
uh but on a quarterly basis the point
that gopal is making on capital gains
that may play out uh you know opposite
to that positivity
yeah I was saying trying to understand
the adjusted for capital gains there is
no one-off in the approval yields
because last two quarters have increased
quite significantly almost 130 basis
point while our tenure of the book is
four years and we were after opinion
that it will improve but it will improve
solely but it has improved quite
significantly in those two quarters so I
just trying to understand there is no
one offender approvalid
the duration at March 22 was roughly
about 3.96 years that number at June was
4.4 years
when you look at September the duration
is at almost about 4.8 years
if that is your question
sure sure
I think this is thank you that's it for
myself
foreign
thank you the next question is from the
line of sanketagoda from spark Capital
please go ahead
yeah thanks for the opportunity
last ratio at 74.3 so sorry to interrupt
if we can take the phone on handset
the the Motorola switched at 74.3 in the
current quarter is is it just because of
the price discounting or or to some
extent we can really uh is it is it true
that the the new policies that is pay as
you go and and the other policies which
which industry has introduced uh has has
also contributed to the loss issues and
if you believe this pay I see those kind
of policies are going to increase in the
contribution
are we seeing structurally higher loss
ratios in motor OD business going ahead
so the answer to your first question is
no because the contribution of those
policies is uh negligible as we speak so
that is I'm going to move the needle not
just now for a long period of time in
our estimate uh the second part of a
question in the long term what will it
do look logically what it should do
we'll have to wait to see what happens
is to price risk more granularly for
better customers so if a better customer
get a cheaper price logically there are
lots of good customer should pay a
higher price now whether the second
thing will happen or not that time will
tell but that is how it should play out
it should you know give us more uh
ability to price appropriate I mean in
the past we've done done secondary
measures of driving behavior right NCB
and you know what not this gives you
ability to price based on driving
behavior and driving distance so you
should price uh your risk better doesn't
mean that it should overall become
cheaper for the whole category
okay
got it sir and and second um see the
personal accident cover uh business
which is highly profitable has seen a
very strong growth when I look at one
age and second quarter number which is
even getting reflected in the uh uh uh
so in the banker Channel numbers what
you have mentioned is it just wanting to
understand further that this these
numbers are sustainable Beyond fi23
because because these channels initially
started started doing business for us
and and therefore they delivered the
growth and and they just wanted to know
the sustainability of these particular
numbers the given given it has been very
strong
what we've been saying is that the
credit uh you know this person is
picking up q1 uh in the first first
quarter we had a base effect of the
previous year's first quarter right uh
you know that was the second the Delta
wave and the you know the business
numbers were very very low uh last year
first quarter so on that beat the first
quarter of this year looks very very
elevated so as a percentage it may not
sustain but in terms of absolute terms
yes we are really optimistic that is
okay so and finally a fundamental
question if I look at the Historical
trend for the industry as a whole uh the
area growth of the industry or or even
for your company is always being higher
compared to gdpi growth but but if you
look at the current year Trend it it is
almost the opposite because because GT5
growth is very strong but but am growth
somehow is struggling
so so because because it's just eight
percent for on year on your business uh
for the for our company so I just wanted
to understand uh uh what what is that
Missing Link which is not driving the
alien growth uh uh a compared to what we
have witnessed in the past
again is a function of uh let's say uh
what kind of business outcomes are you
operating at now at this point of time
so again as we have as you would have
seen and what we have been talking
through is that in so far as our
combined ratios are concerned I think it
is currently slightly at elevated level
than what we would expect it to operate
at so for example you saw the numbers
for Q2 at let's say 105 505.1 half here
was 104.6 so hence to that extent
obviously the relative accretion to cash
flows or electricity asset Center
management will be relatively lower so
that's uh one component that will be a
function of what you see related to
growth second when you specifically look
at in the context of quarter two you
will always find the flows to the
overall assessment of management to be
lower that primarily happens because as
I mentioned in response to one of the
earlier questions q1 is a period where
you see both bulk of the constant
Renewables taking place where you end up
getting the premiums in quarter one
however given that where I mentioned
also that the corporate book generally
tends to have a higher proportion of
reinsurance as per the reinsurance
arrangements those settlements takes
place in quarter two so bulk of the
outflows again happen in Q2 and hence
that exchange and not just this quarter
two if you look at historically in any
of the quarter tools you will find
relatively the flows don't get accrued
in so far as the overall investment book
is concerned to be lower so and hence as
we kind of continue to improve in
breaking down the overall
combined ratios within acceptable
threshold over the next couple of years
is what we have indicated you should
logically get to see a higher proportion
of slows getting approved to the
investment book so that's the second
component the third in line with what we
have indicated I think relative to again
what kind of business mix that you write
for example Health as we indicated it
will not have as much of a long tail of
float compared to let's say motor and at
this point of time I think in so far as
the motor book is concerned given the
relative competitive intensity that we
see in the market we are a bit cautious
our health is doing reasonably well for
us and hence that's also a function of
what kind of approvals and reference to
the overall effect Central management as
we get to see pricing improve in motor
over the next it's a few quarters and
growth comes comes back then obviously
you will start seeing a relatively
higher proportion of approvals happening
to the overall asset Center management
please
before we take the next question a
reminder to the participants please
limit your questions to do a participant
for any follow-up may be requested to
rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
neeraj toshniwal from UBS India please
go ahead
hello
wanted to understand the post deny I
think there have been some uh
uh has some players again started to you
know kind of become more competitive uh
and that is impacting or I want to read
about it
yeah so as as I mentioned uh you know we
are seeing some green shoots in CV we
are seeing some moderation from some
other you know some of the larger uh
traditional players
um in od we are seeing some of the
players now rationalize the aggression
however at the same time there are still
a few players who are very aggressive
our senses that this will not sustain
but you know that is the reason why
we've been saying that we are a bit
cautious in the on damage segment
think about it
so it's been the trend that you've been
talking about for last
actually a couple of years there's been
aggression but it's sustained I mean
generally as you know I think we've
mentioned this many times but generally
we see this aggression tone down after
about a year year and a half this time
it's just in probably because of the
government benefits that people saw up
here we were probably expecting this to
come down you know moderate sooner this
year it's taking a bit more time but the
early signs are early signs are you know
quite quite better uh you know early
signs are positive so we are optimizing
the second half will be uh a bit better
than what we've seen in the first time
and the second half definitely we get
the benefit of lower bees also in terms
of Premium so how how actually uh
overall given the commercial and it's
already doing well and this already pick
up in Hell uh what kind of growth are we
kind of in presently uh taking us for
the full year if any concern that
question I think I answered that
question earlier
you know might say our sense is that
visually what we indicated at the
beginning of the year we remain an
optimistic that we had
thank you
thank you the next question is from the
lineup Avinash Singh from MK Global
please go ahead
yeah hi uh good evening a couple of
questions uh first uh if I look at the
overall you know commercial lines
particularly you know uh uh the
liability that is quite profitable what
you would have you seem to have lost
markets here so either Market has gone
too fast and you have been cautious so
what is driving sort of your Market your
loss in that highly profitable line that
particular liability uh so that's one
and second uh would be more on what is
uh I mean again the media reporting
around this uh we must completely
creative uh
targeting uh Health particular retail of
what uh do you see some kind of a
channel concept there to the yellow
division
so Avinash in terms of liability uh last
year there was launch of a product by
one company last year which
you know is classified as a liability
program which The Authority has now uh
asked the industry not to write so if
you look at our growth uh as it is our
growth you know for uh for Q2 is roughly
about 36.4 percent so our our business
continues to do well uh into the market
share it is only because of that you
know that one company is one product
which we believe right now is not there
in the market that's the that's the
reason that you are seeing market share
drop but the traditional Library
business which is profitable the one
that you're talking about that's
something that we continue to do well
and we are going and became a number one
in uh you know in traditional liability
if you keep on this SQL probability
uh your second question
of course media reports has only come uh
so will there be a channel conflict
because I mean this is I will try to
reach uh you know retail customer retail
health is something where you or anyone
else Drive business a lot through agency
so will there be some kind of a channel
conflict because I mean you need to have
differential pricing otherwise I mean
kind of a you know obtained from data a
day one
so our sense is that this will be this
is something that the authority is also
very keen on so this will uh you know
pick up and take off and our senses are
it will actually increase the
penetration rather than creating Channel
conflict uh we will have to wait to see
what the governance of that entity you
know the understanding that we have at
this point in time it is is that it will
be a industry control controlled entity
as in the shareholding will be largely
distributed across the players with
maybe a technology partner who will uh
also have you know some some stake we
will have to design the governance
mechanism of that entity and the
products that go on there we will have
to see what goes in and you know which
which segments of customers it focuses
on overall we believe it's a it's a
great positive in terms of uh creating
greater awareness because everyone will
talk about it and the fact that it's
something that the regulator is
endorsing it should create a fair
approach to Distribution on on life that
we've been kind of hoping for and
waiting for so we are quite optimistic
about this
okay basically on motor TP losses if
there's three moving parts of course you
have seen three four percent Blended
price high or maybe in the CV maybe
higher second part of post you have you
know uh this motor vehicle act
implementation that probably is kind of
a religious fraud and all and third part
will be of course a inflation cleaning
station that is typically doubled you
can come you know already very extreme
or photographical as well so all these
feet put together you sort of for your
friend for the first half speed that you
are still seeing uh you know a lot of
improvement or scope for improvement
because ultimately at this point it's
estimation and you have been typically
very very conservative what makes you
feel sort of organic with these three
moving Parts is going to improve
um I got to most of the part of police I
didn't write this is the last line what
do you think that you think why do you
think it will improve was that the
question
yeah so I'm saying the price hike has
happened but it's muted but claim
inflation are way very strong I mean in
a motor TV particularly some extreme
claim Awards and then uh of course motor
vehicle act will have positive impact so
there are multiple moving Parts but if I
see uh you know your motor TP kind of a
clean trace of a first half there is
Improvement uh so I mean because I mean
my claims uh uh yeah so my clearance
impression is typically doubled is
closed level is so what is a sort of for
your view I mean you are facing this uh
to go down
yeah so with us your uh your point is
right there are multiple moving parts
and that's why it's very difficult to
predict but if you go back to what gopal
said don't look at a quarterly number
for people lost issues look at an
annualized number if you look at last
year uh and that's what we had kind of
integrated at the beginning of this year
uh to a similar question if you look at
last year our TP loss ratio was 74 uh
for half year it's over 70.1 but it's
better to look at analyze number rather
than just this quarter 66.6 uh to give
you a sense of what we believe is a more
you know reasonably accessible number
having said that I think the point that
you're making in terms of uh claim
inflation you know this is the point
that we've always been making and
accordingly we've had reasonably High
claim inflation numbers
we believe that a lot of companies hold
uh you know significantly lower
percentage of inflation and you know in
a sense that may be inadequate
um but we are quite comfortable with the
inflation number that we are holding
what we want to observe is the frequency
drops that we anticipate because roof
because of the uh the the new motor
vehicle act that we you know earlier
responded to but the frequency drop we
have to watch for before we conclude
that it's actually come through and you
know the reduction in Ford Etc that
you're talking about is coming through
my sense is that we'll give it some time
to uh to to develop for us to build
confidence and talk about a reduced
number uh I hope that explains you what
are the short-term uh thinking is and
what we believe can happen in the long
term
thank you
the next question is from the lineup
anjumandeep from ipaca Securities please
go ahead
yeah hi good evening and thank you for
the opportunity
my question regarding the comment that
you made on the ICICI Bank restarting uh
some of the attachment sales for a home
alone so is this the uh the kind of
benefit product that uh you know we used
to sell earlier because that was very
profitable and used to contribute a
decent amount to our profit if you could
clarify on that thank you so anshuman I
mentioned that it's an Indemnity product
and it's not just this quarter even last
quarter we had indicated that the bank
had restarted selling attachment of
Health indignity uh so that's where the
growth is very strong uh obviously the
product concept is very different from
the original benefit construct and
accordingly profitable profitability
will be very different
thanks a lot that will be all thank you
thank you
the next question is from the lineup
Deepika Mundra from JP Morgan please go
ahead
um thank you thanks sir for taking my
question so this is following up on the
ICICI Bank uh a loan link product uh in
terms of scale is there scope to go back
to the earlier scale of premiums that
were being done even with an Indemnity
product
look at an aggregate relationship with a
bank there are many things that we do
right it's not it's not one product that
we sell with the bank so there is uh SME
business that we do with them there is a
corporate business that we would do with
them there is help business across
different lines be it attachment or in
terms of Indemnity that we do with them
uh in aggregate the relationship is
becoming has become
uh the reason why we wanted to talk
about the health number that we talked
in the opening uh remarks was because
this last year was a a bit of a drag
because the health business the
attachment business has been stopped the
point that we are making is that the
attachment business has started though
the service construct is different from
what it was last year foreign
could you tell us a little bit about the
experience on a renewals that are coming
in from the older books so what would be
the renewal rate of uh older customers
uh and uh in terms of loss experience
between new and old customers what would
be the differential
I'll ask gopal to give you the numbers
but before that I'll just give you the
contribution since you asked that
question about what can we go back just
to give you a sense of the numbers in
aggregate
ICC Bank contribution if you go to two
years back before they took that call
was about five point nine percent last
year dropped over 5.3 percent even
though that big business which we are
sourcing into the attachment went away
we build other we do other uh other
segments other product categories for q1
this year sorry Q2 results become almost
6.1 percent for the whole year it's
about 5.8 percent so in a sense for the
half year we are back to a similar
number that we had in 2021 in terms of
contribution now obviously our business
has gone so is Advanced business is also
going with us coming to your question so
on the on the health renewal uh
percentages that number is that it
ranges between 75 to 80 that's the kind
of retention that we get to see your
other point on what kind of street do we
see in so far as the loss ratios on the
new portfolio and the older portfolio on
the new I think the portfolio of ratio
for bridge again anywhere between 45 to
50 percent
and the old portfolio loss ratios could
range between 75 to 80.
someone asked question uh yeah
the next question is from the line of
druesh pujara from mirabilis please go
ahead uh yeah hi thanks so I have three
questions first is that 48 percent of
the gdpi comes from broker Channel I
think couldn't find anything about
number of Brokers or how has been the
growth on the broker front so can you
talk about that and also do we have a
separate team
yeah
so where to
two segments of business where Brokers
play at this role one is the motor
business all the OEM
uh that MISD business largely comes
through Brokers this could be an oem
controller OEM broker like maruti has
their own broking entity through which
you you get access to the leadership uh
or some of the uh oems work with other
Brokers but it's still a broking
business uh you know in terms of the
business coming through and how we
reflecting our numbers so one is the
motor business which is the OEM driven
mi3 business so that's one the second is
the corporate business uh corporate you
know we one of the few companies which
has a direct sales team so we have
direct relationship management teams
which does Business Development goes to
corporates but we all equally work with
Brokers uh particularly from the sne
segment there's also for uh corporate uh
corporate customers now for the SME and
for corporate customers we have a
separate working team which is
dedicatedly looking at the working
Channel
thank you
ladies and gentlemen due to time
constraint we take that as the last
question
I now found the conference over time
Gupta for closing comments over to you
sir
thank you guys for staying up to listen
to us and let me wish you a wish all of
you a very Happy Diwali on the behalf of
the entire management team of Isis
number thank you and look forward to
interactions our interactions over the
over the quarter thank you so much thank
you ladies and gentlemen on behalf of
icicl Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this conference
we thank you all for joining us and you
may now disconnect your lines